

Silviya Stateva, Ph.D.

Date of Birth: 13/10/1984 Nationality: Bulgarian

View Portfolio

Experienced researcher with a Ph.D. in Biochemistry, currently transitioning into the tech industry. I have a **strong background in analyzing large and complex datasets**, complemented by practical experience in **Python and SQL**. Currently expanding my skills in software quality assurance through a **QA course** at SoftUni, focusing on bug detection, test case creation, and manual testing.

Work History

Postdoc, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal

April 2019 - July 2023

- Led interdisciplinary projects involving data processing and analysis, focusing on protein phosphorylation.
- Managed large datasets and performed statistical analyses to interpret experimental results.
- Employed critical thinking and creativity to analyze complex data, organize experiments, and produce insightful reports.
- Curated and developed a comprehensive database of the *E. coli* phosphoproteome, featuring over 12,000 phosphosites on more than 2,000 gene products, using Django, Python, and PostgreSQL. See Live App

Senior Expert, GMO Lab, Environmental Executive Agency, Ministry of Environment and Water, Sofia, Bulgaria

May 2018 - April 2019

- Conducted sample analysis using advanced molecular biology techniques, such as qPCR, in compliance with ISO and GLP standards.
- Contributed to the evaluation and implementation of new bioanalytical processes.

Postdoc, Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, Sofia, Bulgaria

February 2016 - February 2018

- Managed projects focused on cancer biology, drug discovery, and bionanotechnology.
- Analyzed and processed large datasets related to drug development and nanotechnology, contributing to significant research publications.

Biology related techniques: Mammalian cell culture, cell transfection techniques, SDS-PAGE and Western blots, immunoprecipitation techniques, ELISA, purification and characterization of recombinant proteins, molecular cloning and vector preparation, PCR, site-directed mutagenesis, confocal microscopy, UV-Vis and fluorescence spectroscopy, circular dichroism spectroscopy, QCM, isothermal titration calorimetry, enzymology, cyto- and genotoxicity assays.

Contact Information

✓ digilabsrs@gmail.com

(00359) 0894 061 189







Education

September 2024 - October 2024

QA basics, UniSoft, Sofia, Bulgaria
February 2023 - March 2024

Full Stack Web Development,
CareerFoundry GmbH, Germany
January 2012 - July 2015

 Ph.D. in Biochemistry, Autonomous University of Madrid, Spain

October 2007 - July 2009

- M.S. in Cell Biology, Sofia University 'St. Kliment Ohridski'

October 2003 - July 2007

B.S. in Molecular Biology, Sofia
University 'St. Kliment Ohridski'

Skills

- Strong Critical Thinking Skills
- Complex Problem Solving
- Data Processing & Analysis
- Data Management & Compliance
- HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS
- JavaScript, Python
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL
- GitHub, Git, Jira, Postman
- Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, Outlook)

Languages

Bulgarian (native)

English